Guide to the Sophocles Papas papers, 1900-1998
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 2: 1999 Accession
  - Sophocles Papas, undated (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Sophocles Papas, undated (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Sophocles Papas Banjo Band, undated (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Sophocles Papas' music instrumentals at Yale (Box 41, Folder 15-23)
  - Ted Papas, ca. 1942 (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Ted Papas, ca. 1951 (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - Ted Papas, undated (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Ted Papas at Haines' Point, undated (Box 40, Folder 74)
  - Post-concert reception for Segovia at Papas' house, undated (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Ida Presti, undated (Box 40, Folder 34)
  - Ida Presti, undated (Box 40, Folder 70)
  - Ida Presti, undated (Box 40, Folder 71)
  - Ida Presti, undated (Box 40, Folder 77)
  - Alvino Rey, 1976 (Box 40, Folder 41)
  - Alvino Rey, 1976 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Carl Sandburg, ca. 1961 (Box 40, Folder 38)
  - Carl Sandburg, ca. 1961 (Box 40, Folder 39)
  - Carl Sandburg, ca. 1961 (Box 40, Folder 40)
  - Carl Sandburg, undated (Box 40, Folder 62)
  - Carl Sandburg, ca. 1961 (Box 40, Folder 72)
  - Carl Sandburg, ca. 1961 (Box 40, Folder 88)
  - Carl Sandburg, ca. 1961 (Box 40, Folder 89)
  - Carl Sandburg, ca. 1961 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Guido Santorsola, 1977 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Guido Santorsola, undated (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Andres Segovia, 1935 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Andres Segovia, undated (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Andres Segovia, undated (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Andres Segovia, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 32)
  - Andres Segovia, 1975 (Box 40, Folder 67)
  - Andres Segovia judging at North Carolina School of Arts, undated (Box 40, Folder 85)
  - Andres Segovia, 1969 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Andres Segovia, undated (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Jesus Silva, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 32)
  - Jesus Silva, 1975 (Box 40, Folder 75)
  - Jesus Silva, 1969 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Roy Smeck, undated (Box 40, Folder 73)
  - Philip H. Smith, Jr., 1978 (Box 40, Folder 44)
  - Social gathering at 2000 N St, late 1940s (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - Jane Pickering (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Four toyes from Jane Pickering's lute book
  - J. Pierpont, Jingle Bells (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Thomas B. Pitfield (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Musicianship for guitarists
  - Manuel M. Ponce (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Scherzino Mexicano, arranged by Manuel Lopez Ramos
  - Manuel M. Ponce (Box 9, Folder 18)
    Two pieces: I. Scherzino Mexicano, II. Giga melancolica
  - Theodore Presser (Box 5, Folder 25)
    Scales cadences
  - Programs, reviews, announcements (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Proposals (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Published compositions (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Purcell to Mozart: Fifty-one piano solos in their original form (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Daniel Purcell - Sarabande (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Sergei Rachmaninoff (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Concerto in C Minor, Op. 18
  - S. Ranieri - Method for guitar (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Erno Rapee and Lew Pollack (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Angela mia
  - Kleon Raptakis (Box 16, Folder 29)
    Music history of Greece from 776 BC to 2nd Century AD
  - Oscar Rasbach and Joyce Kilmer (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Trees
  - Maurice Ravel (Box 8, Folder 31)
    Pavane pour une enfante defunte
  - John Reading (Box 19, Folder 30)
    O come all ye faithful
  - Renaissance lute music for the guitar: an anthology of constant delight (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Repertoire Vol. 1, No. 1, October 1951 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Nikolai Rimsky-Korsakow (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Chanson indoue (A Song of India) from the legend "Sadko"
  - Nikolai Rimsky-Korsakow (Box 2, Folder 5)
    The rose enslaves the nightingale
  - Anne Robinson - Flamenco (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - J. Russell Robinson and Spencer Williams - Ringtail Blues (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Arranged by Harry Volpe and Frank Victor
  - Rock-a-bye-baby (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - The role of Italy in the early history of classic guitar: a sidelight on the house of Ricordi (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - The romance of the guitar (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Peter Room (Box 5, Folder 24)
    1, 4, 4, and minor: Guitar technique and song book for beginners
  - Lew Rose Gypsy (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - The Rosette Vol. 2, Nos. 6 and 12; Vol. 3, No. 2, 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - The rosewood book - thirty duets for guitar and flute (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Rusian lullaby (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Ryan's true guitar, containing elementary instruction in music, together with a complete guide by which the learner may become a good accompanist, 1873 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Camille Saint-Saens (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Mon coeur s'ouvre a ta voix (My heart at thy sweet voice), Cantabile from "Samson et Dalila"
  - German Salinas (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Carl Sandburg - correspondence (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Carl Sandburg - correspondence (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Helga Sandburg - correspondence (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - G. C. Santisteban (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Carcassi method for the guitar
  - Guido Santorsola - correspondence (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Guido Santorsola (Box 21, Folder 7-8)
    Principios ormonicos de los sonidos otractivos y otraidos
  - Guido Santorsola (Box 8, Folder 21)
    Three airs of court: 1. Preludio, 2. Aria, 3. Finale
  - Gaspar Sanz (Box 19, Folder 30)
    Pavana; Zarabanda
  - Sarabande (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Erik Satie (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
    Gymnopedie I
  - Alessandro Scarlatti - Gavotte (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Alessandro Scarlatti - Gavotte (Box 9, Folder 32)
    Arranged by Elisabeth papas Smith
  - Alessandro Scarlatti - Gavotte for guitar solo (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Domenico Scarlatti (Box 8, Folder 12)
    9 sonatas
  - Domenico Scarlatti (Box 9, Folder 12)
    9 sonatas, Vol. 2
  - Domenico Scarlatti (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Domenico Scarlatti (Box 8, Folder 13)
    Sonata longo 238
  - Domenico Scarlatti (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Sonata longo 483
  - Scarlet ribbons (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Arranged by Loris O. Chobanian
  - SCG Bulletin, assorted issues, Vols. 1-9, 1948-1955 (Box 14, Folder 15-40)
  - SCG Bulletin, assorted issues, Vols. 11-24, 1958-1960, 1964-1971 (Box 15, Folder 1-23)
  - John W. Schaum (Box 6, Folder 4)
    John W. Schaum piano course: pre-A book
  - John W. Schaum (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Theory lessons in loose leaf form for individual or class instruction: Book 1
  - John W. Schaum (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Theory lessons in loose leaf form for individual or class instruction: Book 2
  - John W. Schaum (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Theory lessons in loose leaf form for individual or class instruction: Book 3
  - William Scher (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Veil dance
  - Schirmer's American folk-songs series: Set 14 - songs of the hill folk (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Arranged by John Jacob Niles
  - Harvey Schmidt (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Try to remember
  - Heinrich Schneider (Box 19, Folder 30)
    Kleine melodie
  - Franz Schubert (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Allegretto in C minor
  - Scot Textor - US Air Force Blue (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Ben Ludlow
  - Scrapbook (Box 42)
  - Ray Sealey (Box 18, Folder 5)
    A circle of tears
  - Seattle Classic Guitar Society Vol. IV, No. 5, Vol. XV, No. 6, 1970, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 15-16)
  - Seattle Classic Guitar Society Vol. VI, No. 7, Vol. VII, No. 4, 1972-1973 (Box 16, Folder 24-25)
  - Peter Seeger - The Folksinger's guitar guide (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Andres Segovia (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Andres Segovia (Box 9, Folder 16)
    Diatonic major and minor scales
  - Andres Segovia (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Andres Segovia (Box 16, Folder 28)
    The guitar and myself
  - Andres Segovia (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Lessons No. 11 and 12 from Follies of My Youth (Le peche de ma jeunesse)
  - Andres Segovia (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Prelude in chords
  - Andres Segovia (Box 8, Folder 28)
    Slur exercises and chromatic octaves
  - Andres Segovia (Box 8, Folder 45)
    Two pieces: 1. Estudio
  - J. Serradell (Box 1, Folder 1)
    La golondrina (The swollow) Mexican folk song
  - J. Serradell (Box 18, Folder 5)
    La golondrina
  - George Sesoko (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Cherry blossom
  - 700 years of music for the classic guitar (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Bob Sheeley (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Anita Sheer and Harry Berlow (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Flamenco guitar for beginners
  - Robert Shieby (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Wayne D. Shieby, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    International inventory of musical sources: report of the Joint US Committee on Activities
  - Jean Sibelius - Finlandia (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Jean Sibelius - Valse Triste (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Jesus Silva - correspondence (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Jerry Silverman (Box 6, Folder 10)
    A folksinger's guide to note reading and music theory: a manual for the folk guitarist
  - Guy Simeone - Petenera (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Thomas Simmons (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Noble Sissle, Sidney Bechet and James Tolliver (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Polka dot stomp - arranged by Harry Volpe and Frank Victor
  - Six authentic songs and dances of Moscow gypsies (Box 2, Folder 34)
    Arranged by Vladimir Bobri and V. Gabaeff
  - Six lute pieces of the Renaissance (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Elisabeth Papas Smith - correspondence (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Elisabeth Papas Smith - manuscripts (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Elisabeth Papas Smith (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Smith's theory book for guitarist covering all scales and intervals
  - Elisabeth Papas Smith, Speech used for book signings (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - J. Morgan Smith, Jr. (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - William J. Smith (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Smith's folk song tenor guitar course
  - Smith's 200 songs for ukelele (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Snyder-Higgins comprehensive guitar method: student book (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Snyder-Higgins comprehensive guitar method: teacher's manual (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Society information (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Society of the Classical Guitar Teacher listings, January 1958 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Songs for guitar Vol. 1 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Songs we sing (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Ferdinand Sor (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Andres Segovia: studies for the guitar
  - Ferdinand Sor (Box 20, Folder 21-23)
    Compositions pour la guitare par Ferdinand Sor
  - Ferdinand Sor (Box 20, Folder 25-30)
  - Ferdinand Sor (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Ferdinand Sor (Box 20, Folder 24)
    Divertissement
  - Ferdinand Sor (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Ferdinand Sor (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Grand solo
  - Ferdinand Sor (Box 19, Folder 30)
    Menuet; Waltz No. 3; Estudio de Sor
  - Ferdinand Sor (Box 20, Folder 31)
    Metodo completo para guittarra
  - Ferdinand Sor (Box 20, Folder 35)
    Miscellaneous pieces - oversized
  - Ferdinand Sor (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Sixty short pieces for guitar: Vol. 1, Nos. 1-38
  - Ferdinand Sor (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Sixty short pieces for guitar: Vol. 2, Nos. 39-60
  - Ferdinand Sor (Box 1, Folder 76)
    Theme varie
  - Soundboard, selected issues, Vols. 3-9, 1976-1983 (Box 14, Folder 1-12)
  - Spain - collections (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Spain - journals, 1935-1936, 1958, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Spain - methods (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Spain - solos (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Spain - technical studies (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Spanish folksong (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Spanish romance (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Francesco Spinacino (Box 1, Folder 69)
    La Bernadina de Josquin
  - William C. Stahl (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Stal's international banjo method
  - John Stainer - Harmony (Box 7, Folder 19)
    Novello's music primers and educational series
  - James Stewart (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Alessandro Stradella (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Cosi amor mi fai languir
  - Student guitarist's delight: Vol. 1 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Student guitarist's delight: Vol. 2 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Sunny Side! The Kingston Trio (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Sweden - collections (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Sweden - methods (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Elliot Sweetland (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Spanish guitar note speller
  - Switzerland - technical studies (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Jim and Sylvia Symington (Box 1, Folder 19)
    It takes time to know a country
  - Thomas Tapper (Box 15, Folder 24)
    Child's own book of great musicians - Handel
  - Thomas Tapper (Box 15, Folder 25)
    Child's own book of great musicians - Haydn
  - Thomas Tapper (Box 15, Folder 26)
    Child's own book of great musicians - Liszt
  - Francisco Tarrega (Box 1, Folder 68)
    Danza odalisca
  - Francisco Tarrega (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Francisco Tarrega (Box 19, Folder 30)
    Prelude II
  - Harry A. Taussig (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Instrumental techniques of American folk guitar
  - Techniques - miscellaneous (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Tel-address book (Box 24)
  - George Philipp Telemann (Box 19, Folder 30)
    Andante and allegro (for two guitars) arranged by Len Williams
  - Georg Philipp Telemann (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Fantasie
  - Term papers/reports (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Text manuscripts and oversize transposition wheel (Box 28)
  - John Thompson (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Book for boys for piano
  - John Thompson (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Thompson's modern course for the piano: the first grade book
  - Moreno Torroba (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Treasure chest of famous marches (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Peter Ilich Tschaikowsky (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Dance of candy fairy (Nutcracker Suite)
  - Peter Ilich Tschaikowsky (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Symphonic skeleton scores: No. 2 - Symphony 6 in B minor - Pathetic
  - Tumbalalalaika and sixteen other Jewish songs for singing in English (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Arranged by Teddy Schwartz
  - Tunes you like: your favorite songs made easy to play (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Arranged by Mark Nevin
  - Turkey - duets (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Twenty easy pieces arranged by Sophocles Papas (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Twenty-five carols from the Oxford book of carols for schools (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Arranged by Eileen Stickley
  - Two easy Christmas carols for the guitar (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Two lute pieces (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - B. W. A. Uray (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Study in E major
  - US - articles (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - US - collections (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - US - methods and teaching aids (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - US - programs (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - US - solos (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - US - songs (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - US - songs printed in Greek (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Sylvia Van Clief and Florence Heide (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Holidays! Holidays! A collection of twenty-one songs to play and sing in the holiday spirit
  - Giuseppe Verdi (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Di provenza il mar (What has made your heart grow cold) Germont's aria in the 2nd act of "La Traviata"
  - F. Dudleigh Vernor and Byron D. Stokes (Box 1, Folder 20)
    The sweetheart of Sigma Chi
  - Heitor Villa-Lobos (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Antonio Vivaldi (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Julio A. Vocos Luque (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Romanza No. 2
  - Harry Volpe and Frank Victor (Box 7, Folder 1)
    The new handy guitar method: modern plectrum style
  - Bernard Wagness (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Piano course - book one
  - Washington Guitar Society (Box 38, Folder 21)
    Artwork for logo
  - Washington Guitar Society, December 14, 1949 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    Program
  - Washington Guitar Society oral history (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Sylvius Leopold Weiss - Fuga (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Sylvius Leopold Weiss - Gigue (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Sylvius Leopold Weiss - Prelude and fugue (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - White Christmas (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Margaret Wigham (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Musical moods in all keys for piano solo
  - World classics for the guitar (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - World's favorite solos for classic guitar (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Yaa Amponsaa, arranged by Yaw Nyame Asiedu (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - George Yeatman (Box 19, Folder 29)
- Series 3: 2011 Accession, 1940s-2003
  This series consists of a collection of newspaper and magazine clippings, postcards (some with correspondence to Elisabeth Papas-Smith), stamps, and photographs collected by Elisabeth Papas-Smith. Images and articles relate to guitars and other fretted instruments, popular music and musicians, and Sophocles Papas and friends.
  - I, circa 1990s (Box 42, Folder 1)
    Postcards, clippings of guitars and other fretted instruments in art, photograph of English classical guitarists and museum guitar displays
  - II, circa 1970-1996 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    Postcards, stamps, clippings of guitars and other fretted instruments in art, photograph of lute player in Sophocles Papas living room
  - III, circa 1999 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    Clippings of Braque, Gris, Picasso works of art featuring guitars
  - IV, circa 1996-2000 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    Stamp, postcards, and clippings of musicians and guitars
  - V, circa 1940s-2001 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    Postcards and clippings of musicians and guitars, photographs of Sophocles Papas, Carlos Montoya, Charlie Byrd, Carl Sandburg and others
  - VI, circa 2000 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    Clippings of musicians and guitars
  - VII, circa 2001-2002 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - VIII, circa 2000-2002 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    Postcards, clippings of musicians and guitars
  - IX, circa 2001-2003 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - X, circa 1991-2003 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - XI, circa 2001-2002 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    Clippings of The Beatles and Alia
  - XII, circa 2002 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    Clippings of lutes, ouds, ancient fretted instruments in art
  - XIII, circa 2001-2002 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    Mostly funny, humorous drawings and cartoon clippings
  - XIV, circa 2000-2001 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    Clippings of women and guitars, photograph of Dorothy Perrenoud